<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>On the front page on Programme 10%</title><link>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/</link><description>Recent content in On the front page on Programme 10%</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shedding light on…n°2 // Mobile applications: what are the security issues for their distribution outside OS stores?</title><link>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/2022-02-18_eclairage_sur_os/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/2022-02-18_eclairage_sur_os/</guid><description>Until now, mobile applications have been distributed almost exclusively through the application stores of operating system developers, on their own terms. These terms are changing under pressure from publishers on the one hand, and with the help of ongoing national and international regulatory changes on the other. In the second issue of its “Shedding light on&amp;hellip;” series, the PEReN takes a closer look at the technical and security issues related to this opening, particularly for the end users.</description></item><item><title>Shedding light on…n°1 // Interoperability</title><link>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/2021-10-08_eclairage_sur_interoperabilite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 14:24:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/2021-10-08_eclairage_sur_interoperabilite/</guid><description>Through the &amp;ldquo;Shedding light on…&amp;rdquo; series of article, PEReN proposes elements of technical analysis on a wide variety of topics related to the regulation of online digital platforms. In this first article, PEReN discusses the notion of interoperability and the forms and degrees this notion can cover.</description></item><item><title>Convention signed between PEReN and the French Competition Authority</title><link>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/convention-peren-adlc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/convention-peren-adlc/</guid><description>The French Competition Authority and PEReN have signed a convention outlining the conditions under which PEReN will provide technical assistance to the French Competition Authority in its missions.</description></item><item><title>Publication of a study on evaluation methods for content recommandation algorithms</title><link>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/publication-study-evaluation-methods-algorithmes-dgmic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/publication-study-evaluation-methods-algorithmes-dgmic/</guid><description>The DMGIC, as part of its participation to an international multi-stakeholder working group on the diversity of online content, commissioned PEReN and Inria/Regalia to conduct a feasibility study evaluating the conditions under which audits of content recommendation algorithms would be possible.</description></item><item><title>Creation of PEReN</title><link>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/creation_du_peren/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 08:47:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>10pourcent.etalab.studio/en/actualites/creation_du_peren/</guid><description>PEReN has been created following the publication of decree n°2020-1102 on the 31 August, 2020. It will be placed under the joint authority of &lt;strong>Bruno Le Maire&lt;/strong>, the Minister of Economy and Finance, &lt;strong>Roselyne Bachelot&lt;/strong>, the Minister of Culture, and &lt;strong>Cédric O&lt;/strong>, the Secretary of State for Digital Affairs.</description></item></channel></rss>